# **Emily B. Siegel**

Data Scientist and Geoscientist with 9+ years experience achieving actionable insights through analyzing and integrating diverse datasets. Passion for problem-solving and a reputation for mastering new roles, responsibilities, technologies, and communicating complex information to nontechnical audiences.

#### **PROJECTS**

- Starbucks Customer Segmentation using K-Means Clustering
- Breast Cancer Detection in Mammograms using Convolutional Neural Networks
- Classifying Passive vs. Active Revenge in Related Subreddits using NLP
- Predicting Ames, Iowa Real Estate Prices with Linear Regression

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Well Data Labs,** Denver, CO — Data Research Analyst & Support Analyst

- Applied best practices in statistical analysis to drive business value and ROI to all stakeholders both internally on the Data Science team, across the organization and externally to clients.
- Validated, tested, and monitored machine learning models' performance and functionality. Standardized accuracy metrics and optimized testing workflow.
- Automated high-frequency time series data wrangling and analyses using Excel VBA and Python. Integrated python scripts in custom built dashboards.
- Coauthored a peer-reviewed paper, client case studies, and blog posts that address key market needs while proposing data-driven solutions and strategies.
- Built 4 data reviews for use in board meetings and presented them to the entire company of 35+ people during quarterly all-hands meetings.
- Tracked product usage, deployed customer retention initiatives, and developed technical documentation with every new release.

## **Reliance OFS (formerly FMC Tech),** Denver, CO — Log Analyst

AUG 2015 - FEB 2019

- Due to newly acquired technology and my previous pulsed neutron expertise, I implemented a new data service, increasing revenue and bringing in 3 new clients.
- \* Trained 2 new analysts on all department functions and created instructional technical manuals, reference materials, and workflows.
- Assessed wellbore integrity and identified potential casing and cement issues to maximize the efficiency of field operations while ensuring safety.

## Baker Hughes, Denver, CO — Geoscientist / Team Lead

APRIL 2013 - AUG 2015

- Led the Cased Hole Petrophysics team of 5 people within the Reservoir Development group. Resulted in 600+ successfully delivered projects yearly.
- Processed and analyzed data using various petrophysical techniques and technologies to provide and present solutions to clients.
- Vital internal role mentoring and teaching data processing techniques, expanding the company's Cased Hole business internationally to South American countries.

#### (720) 355-3708

emilybsiegel@gmail.com LinkedIn GitHub Data Science Portfolio

#### **EDUCATION**

### **General Assembly**

Data Science Immersive
JUNE 2021- SEPT 2021

#### **University of Vermont**

B.S. Geology, Minor Studio Art AUG 2008 - MAY 2012

#### **SKILLS**

## Core Competencies:

Analytics + Research Machine Learning Project Management Technical Writing Presenting

Software: Computational notebooks (Jupyter) | Data visualization (Spotfire & PowerBI) | CRM (Salesforce) | Code repos (GitHub & BitBucket) | Software product planning (Pivotal Tracker) | Product UX (Pendo) | AWS | Adobe Creative

#### **LANGUAGES**

Python | SQL | Excel VBA | Bash | Hebrew | French

#### **PAPERS**

SPE 204145 (2021)
Employing a Suite of
Machine-Learning
Algorithms in a Holistic
Approach to Trouble-Stage
Recognition and Failure
Diagnostics